Guide to the Roy Rosenzweig papers, 1934-2007
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Roy Rosenzweig papers
1934-2007
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Roy Rosenzweig
C0038
49.5 linear feet (98 boxes; 9,776 electronic files)
The collection largely documents his research and writing through articles, notes, and correspondence on New York Central Park, Worcester (Massachusetts), labor, and digital humanities work. Although the collection dates from 1934, there are many facsimilies of documents, particularly on Central Park, that contain information prior to 1934.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
With the exception of Series 9, there are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Deborah Kaplan in 2008-2009.
Biographical Information
Roy Alan Rosenzweig received his Ph.D. in history from Harvard University in 1978. In 1981, Rosenzweig accepted a position in the George Mason University History Department and became one of the most popular professors at the university until his untimely death in 2007. He was a prolific writer, not only in print but also in many other forms of media, such as CD-ROMs, documentary film, and the Internet. In 1994, his strong interest in technology led to his founding of the Center for History and New Media at George Mason University, widely recognized in the history and humanities fields for producing ground-breaking educational and research communication technologies.
Scope and Content
The collection largely documents his research and writing through articles, notes, and correspondence on New York Central Park, Worcester (Massachusetts), labor, and digital humanities work. In addition, the collection contains almost complete runs of rare history and humanities periodicals such as Radical History Review Newsletter, Historical Methods Newsletter, History Microcomputer Review, Radical Teacher, Cultural Correspondence, and Radical America. His interest and work with oral history is reflected in the Northern Virginia Oral History Project files. Although the collection dates from 1934, there are many facsimilies of documents, particularly on Central Park, that contain information prior to 1934.
Series 1 contains Roy Rosenzweig's academic correspondence from 1969-2007. Much of the series consists of correspondence regarding collaboration, panels, papers, letters of recommendation, awards, research permissions and conferences. This series is arranged alphabetically and then by date.
Series 2 contains books, pamphlets, newsclippings, papers, xeroxes, magazines and other research materials on labor history. This series contains the book Eight Hours for What We Will: Workers and Leisure in an Industrial City, 1870-1921. In addition to research about labor and leisure, this series contains research about the 1930s such as unemployment and The New Deal and Works Progress Administration (WPA). Topics such as unions, general worker's rights and radicalism also appear in this series. The series is arranged alphabetically and then by date.
The largest series in the collection, Series 3 contains magazines, pamphlets, government documents, books, newsclippings, papers, xeroxes and note cards about New York City and Central Park. A large portion of this research focuses on entertainment, public works, budgets, planning, landscape architecture, jobs, crime and events in Central Park and surrounding areas. This research culminated in Rosenzweig's acclaimed 1992 book (with co-author Elizabeth Blackmar) The Park and the People: A History of Central Park. This series is arranged alphabetically and then by date.
Series 4 contains research that culminated in Rosenzweig's 1998 book (with co-author David Thelen) The Presence of the Past: Popular Uses of History in American Life. Survey data regarding demographics, papers, reports, variables, public history, and information and research regarding the ways in which Americans interpret and apply the past is found in this series. This series is arranged alphabetically and then by date.
Series 5 contains pamphlets, guides, papers, articles, xeroxes and magazines about oral history such as oral history interviewing guides, recording guides, plans for oral history courses and the Northern Virginia Oral History Project. This series is arranged alphabetically and then by date.
Series 6 contains information about the Center for History and New Media as well as an array of research which culminated in Rosenzweig's 2006 book (with co-author Daniel Cohen) Digital History: A Guide to Gathering, Preserving, and Presenting the Past on the Web. In addition to research used for the book, the series contains both guides and ideas for using technology in the classroom and to enhance academic and popular research. This series is arranged alphabetically and then by date.
Series 7 contains CDs, DVDs, cassettes and computer disks used by Rosenzweig both to save writing and for instructional purposes. This series is arranged alphabetically and then by date.
Series 8 contains oversized materials such as photographs, prints, posters and an atlas. Of note in this series is a 1934 photograph of Franklin Roosevelt in leg braces. This series is arranged alphabetically and then by date.
Series 9 consists of three folders of electronic files that date from 1995-2007. The first folder "files archived 2003-2006" contains files on his work at the Center for History and New Media, including digital history projects, grant proposals, and materials for Clio Wired, the digital history course he taught. There is also a folder of attachments that appears to be documents that were attached to email messages. The second folder consists of research and drafts for a book project "The Future of the Past" that was published posthumously. The third file contains "writings," and the files mostly consist of research for publications, both digital and hardcopy, There are also a number of documents on the functioning of the CHNM, including meetings, budgets, and presentations. These files are restricted.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1969-2007
Series 2: Labor History, 1960-1990
Series 3: The Park and the People, 1980s-1990s
Series 4: The Presence of the Past, 1990-1999
Series 5: Oral History, 1970-2007
Series 6: Digital History, 1988-2007
Series 7: Media, 1980s-2007
Series 8: Oversize, 1934-1972
Series 9: Electronic Files, 1995-2007
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds oral history collections as well as the George Mason University records.
There are several runs of rare history and humanities periodicals from the Rosenzweig collection that can be found through the GMU Libraries online catalog.
Index Terms
Persons:
Rosenzweig, Roy.
Corporate Names:
George Mason University. Center for History and New Media.
Geographical Names:
Central Park (New York, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Digital Humanities Centers.; History--Study and teaching.; Labor--History.; Oral history.
Contents List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1969-2007; (9 boxes)
  Academic correspondence arranged alphabetically and then by date.
  - AASLH, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AHA, 1986 - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AHA Perspectives, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Heritage, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Studies Association, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arena Stage, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arlington Freedman's Village, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ASA, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Berger, Howard, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Borders Bookstore, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Botein Prize, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brody, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Budapest and NYC Collaboration, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Can Historians Speak to a Wider Audience?, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1972-2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - COSA, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Frederick Historic Sites, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - German Peoples History, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Geschictswerkstatt, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - History in the Classroom, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - History Teaching Network, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - JAAS, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Journal of American History, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Life and Labor, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Local Virginia High Schools, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - London Correspondence, 1971 - 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Mass Culture, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Movimento Operaio e Socialista, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Museum Book Articles, 1980s (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Nationhood and Citizenship, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - New York Historical Society, 1980s (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - OAH, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - OAH and OHMAR, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - OAH Comments, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - OAH Conference, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - OAH Panel, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - OAH Panel, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Oberlin, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Parks Movie Script Ideas, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Permissions, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Presence of the Past, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Presence of the Past, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Presenting the Past, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Presenting the Past, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Public History, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Scarcity or Abundance?, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Smithsonian Museum Planning Meetings, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Smithsonian Paper, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Stearns, Peter, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Survey Book, Presence of the Past, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Teaching In-service Program, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The Park and the City, 1990s (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Park and the People, 1990s (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Park and the People, 1990s (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Thelen, David, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Tompkins Square, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - US and Hungary Meetings, 1987 - 1989 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - War and Memory, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Who Built America?, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Series 2: Labor History, 1960-1990s; (23 boxes)
  Labor History research generated mostly in the 1980s.
  - 1930s Research, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1930s Research, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1930s Research, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1930s Research, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1930s Research, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1930s Research, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - A Guide to Working Class History, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - A History of the American Labor Movement, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - A History of the Steelworker's Union, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - A Look Back: Pages Out of American Labor's Past, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - A Man Who Made a Difference, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - AHA Panel on The Relationship Between Work and Leisure, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Air America, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Alcohol Republic, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - American Heritage Ideas, 1980s (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - American Heritage Interviews, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - American Heritage/AHA, 1980s (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - American Labor History, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - American Labor History Series: Subject Papers, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - American Labor History: A Guide to Resources in the Michigan State University Libraries, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - America's Labor History: The Lowell Story, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Amoskeag and First Person America, 1978, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Between a Rock and A Hard Place: A History of Sweatshops, 1820-Present, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Boston Workers: A Labor History, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Boston Workers: The Boston Irish Political Machines (Worcester Files), 1830-1973 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Boston's Labor Movement, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - British Labor Movement, 1980s (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - British Labor Movement, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - C.L.R. James: His Life and Work, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Catton, Bruce, 1980s (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Coal in Conspiracy, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Commonwealth of Toil, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Communities Try to Organize, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Conference: The New Labor History of New England, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Talk "Eight Hours in Context", 1980s (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Counter: Planning on the Shop Floor, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Dissent: The World of the Blue Collar Worker, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Drink Notes, 1870-1889 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Drink Notes, 1870-1889 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Drink Notes, 1890-1920 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Drink Notes, 1890-1920 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Drink Notes, 1890-1920 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Drink Secondary, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Drink Secondary, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Drinks and Parks: Note Cards, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Dulles: America Learns, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Eight Hours Publicity, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Eight Hours Research, Notes on Manuscript, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Eight Hours Research, Notes on Manuscript, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Eight Hours Reviews, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Eight Pamphlets about Working Classes/Labor History, 1969-1973 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Enumerations, 1870s-1880s (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Enumerations, 1870s-1880s (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Essays on the Social Relations of Work and Labor, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Farm Labor Organizing, 1905-1967 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Female Revolution as the Basis for Social Revolution, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Film Quarter Library: Labor Films, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - General/Perspective, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Gompers, Samuel, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Gonna Rise Again: Economic Organizing for Hard Times, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Haymarket Revisited, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - History as Indoctrination, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - History From Below, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - History Magazines, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Imperialism: An Exchange, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Industrial Workers of the World, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Itinerary of Mr. A.M. Parker, 1880s (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Labor Defender, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Labor History Documents, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Labor History Documents, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Labor History: Work, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Labor History: Work, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Labor Play, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Labor Play, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Labor Research: Articles, Magazines, Pamphlets, Papers, 1930s (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Labor's Heritage, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Legitimation and Resistance in Class Societies, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Liberation, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Life and Times in Shoe City: The Shoe Workers of Lynn, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Manifesto of the Communist International, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Marx and the Proletariat, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Marxism and Black Radicalism in America, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - McKinney, Ernst Rice, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - McKinney, Ernst Rice, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Men Out of Work: Unemployment in English Towns, 1970s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Milwaukee History, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Mission Hill, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Mission Hill Boston 200 Series, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Mission Hill Plant, 1970s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Movement Songbook, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Mr. Block Cartoons, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Muste, Abraham, 1930s (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - NCSS Club, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - NCSS Club, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notes on Unemployment in America and Britain, 1970s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - OAH Panel on The Social Production of Leisure, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - On the Job, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Out of the Jungle, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Paynter, Will and Welsh Miners, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Preamble: A Constitution of the Industrial Workers of the World, 1906 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Production Code Administration (PCA), 1970s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Production Code Administration (PCA), 1970s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Production Code Administration (PCA), 1970s-1980s (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - PWA and Industry, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Radical Historian Newsletters, 1973-1976 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - RESIST Newsletter, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Rostow's Stages of Economic Growth, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Shoe Factory and Plant, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Snake Hill to Spring Bank, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Sociability of Workers and the Working Class in Comparative Perspective, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Sojka, Gregory S., 1970s (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Soldiers and Strikers, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Solidarity UAW: Forty Years of Struggle, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Songs of American Labor, Industrialization, and the American Work Experience, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Sports and Drinking Note Cards, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Sports and Drinking Note Cards, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - SSHA Panel, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Steinway: A New York Story, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Strikes and Racketeering, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Talkin' Union, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - The American Jitters: A Year of the Slump, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - The Annenberg CPB Project, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - The Birth of a Local Union: The History of UAW Local 674, Norwood, Ohio, 1933-1940 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - The Case for Abolishing ROTC, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - The Chicago Strike of 1894, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - The Conflict Over the Saloon, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - The Grand Illusion, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - The Great Flint Sit-Down Strike Against General Motors, 1936-1937 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - The ILGWU: A Union That Fights for Lower Wages, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - The Maryland Historian Labor Issue, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - The Narrative of Hosea Hudson, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - The New Deal in Historical Perspective, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - The New Deal: The Conservative Achievements of Liberal Reform, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - The Political Economy of Women's Liberation, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - The Poor Man's Burden, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - The Power in Our Hands, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Union, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - The River Ran Red, 1892 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - The Socialist Spirit, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - The Subversion of Collective Bargaining, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - The Working American, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Their Morals and Ours, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - They Can't Run the Office Without Us: 60 Years of Clerical Work, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Two Steel Contracts, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Unemployed Councils in St. Petersburg, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Unemployment Folsom Papers, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Unemployment Insurance System: Past, Present, and Future, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Unemployment Labor History Conference, 1980s (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Unemployment Notes, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Unemployment Notes, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Unemployment Notes, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Unemployment Notes, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Unemployment Notes, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Unemployment Notes, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Unemployment Notes (NUWM), 1980s (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Unemployment Outline and Early Projects, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Unemployment, Marcher's Registration Blanks, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - USA The Labor Revolt, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Violations of Free Speech and Rights of Labor Reports, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Walking Tours in Shoe City, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Walvin: "Leisure and Society", 1978 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Waterfront Supercargo, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Weaver Social History Collection, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - What's Happening to the American Worker?, 1960s-1970s (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - When Southern Labor Stirs, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - When Southern Labor Stirs, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Who Built America? CD Rom Material, 1990s (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Who Built America? CD Rom Material, 1990s (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Who Built America? Census, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Who Built America? Chapter 4, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Who Built America? Chapter 4, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Who Built America? Chapter 4, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Who Built America? Chapter 4, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Who Built America? Chapters 1-3, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Who Built America? Chapters 1-3, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Who Built America? Documents, Imprinted, World Records, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Who Built America? Film, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Who Built America? GMU Grant, 1991-1992 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Who Built America? II Elements, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Who Built America? II Excursions, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Who Built America? II Excursions, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Who Built America? II NEH Grant, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Who Built America? II NEH Grant, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Who Built America? Old memos, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Who Built America? Possible Documents, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Who Built America? Research, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Who Built America? Research, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Who Built America? Research, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Who Built America? Research, 1990s (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Who Built America? Research, 1990s (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Who Built America? Research, 1990s (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Who Built America? Research, 1990s (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Who Built America? Sound, 1990s (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Who Built America? Sound, 1990s (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Who Built America? The Teacher's Handbook, 1990s (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Who Built America? Unemployment Material, 1990s (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Who Built America? Worth, Bedford and ASHP, 1990s (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Women and the Socialist Party, 1901-1914, 1980s (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Women in American Labor History, 1980s (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Worcester Ethnicity, 1980s (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Worcester Ethnicity, 1980s (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Worcester Ethnicity, 1980s (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Worcester General, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Worcester General, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Worcester Labor, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Worcester Labor, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Worcester Newspaper Index, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Worcester Newspaper Index, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Worcester Pamphlet, 1980s (Box 30, Folder 1)